- What I worry about here is like,
Citadel securities to me is not the voice
to be saying, we care about consumer protection.
- I really think as an industry,
we need to take those issues really seriously,
because the SEC is never going to allow capital markets
to come on chain unless we can prove
that they're fair and transparent.
- One of the things that I still have PTSD over is 2022,
where a major contributing factor,
I was at a DeFi protocol at that time.
And I was so furious because there was so much demonization
of DeFi in the press narrative during the crypto crash.
And we were all like, it's not DeFi
that screwed this up, guys.
It's actually SeFi masquerading as DeFi.
- We were in this next creepy part, because it got worse.
So then they were like, okay, let's point the agents
at brand new contracts that were just put out
into the ecosystem with no known issue.
- Within a short period of time, the agents found
two zero-day exploits.
Zero days, essentially, just like the builders
have had zero days to fix any vulnerabilities
following release, and they executed exploits.
And they made money that costs more
than what the agents cost.
- Hi, all, and welcome to Decks in the City,
where the wallets are cold and the takes are hot.
First, we have Jesse, web3 prosecutor,
turned web3 protector at Ribbit Capital.
- Hi, everyone.
- And V from the SEC to web3.
- What's up?
- And I'm your host, Catherine, our KK,
fluent in TradFi and conversant in deep tech
over at Starquare.
And V and I are reporting live from our hotel rooms
at the Pluck Chain Association Summit in Washington, DC.
So we've been looking into some good stuff,
but before we get started, here's a word from our sponsors
that make this show possible.
- Are you a builder who needs to add on-chain trading
to your product?
- The Uniswap Trading API from Uniswap Labs
offers plug-and-play access
to some of the deepest liquidity in crypto.
It's on-chain execution at an enterprise level.
More liquidity, less complexity.
Visit hub.uniswap.org to learn more.
- Before we get going, remember, we're lawyers,
but we're not your lawyers.
Nothing you hear on Decks in the City
is legal or financial advice,
and it doesn't create an attorney-client relationship.
For the fine print, check unchainedcrypto.com.
So we have a jam-packed episode today
because as usual, there has been so much going on
in crypto, mostly good, but some bad.
And speaking of bad, the industry was rocked the other day
with a very strongly worded, lengthy article
from Citadel Securities.
So we jump in and tell us more about this letter
and why they sent a letter and all the things.
- Sure, so first off, excuse the bed in the background.
I tried to make it.
- That's not good.
I'm not really good at it, so.
- I also made my bed.
- Is there so much to feel about this person here?
- Yeah, I usually don't do that in hotel rooms.
- Okay, so let's talk about Citadel.
So this week, Citadel Securities,
our favorite little market maker
and the king of payment for order flow,
submitted a comment letter to the SEC
on tokenized equities and so-called DeFi trading protocols.
And this letter is fascinating
because I think it tells you exactly how a major incumbent
thinks about this next potential chapter
of market structure, right?
So here's the gist of their position.
So Citadel says they support the idea.
- Sorry to interrupt you, before we get there,
'cause I got this question and I know the answer,
but I want you to explain it.
Why would Citadel send a letter to the SEC?
Like, what is the point?
Can I just send a letter to the SEC?
Like, give us more info on just the background
of where this came from.
- Yeah, so I mean, the general answer is yes.
Anyone can submit a letter, a comment,
a question to the SEC.
Usually this takes place in the context
of a formal rulemaking, right?
Where the agency, the SEC actually invites comment letters
from the public.
I think what probably prompted this particular letter
is Chair Atkins has been talking a lot recently
about something called the DeFi Innovation Exemption.
And I think that has made a lot of,
so I think it's made crypto very excited
about the possibilities there.
But I think it has made some of the incumbents
and tradfi very nervous
because he has not yet said what it's going to look like
and how it's going to impact the current market
and market structure, right?
So I think that is probably what prompted this letter.
So in the letter, they do say they support the idea
of tokenization and they acknowledge all the things
that we know, right?
The efficiency gains, faster settlement,
investor choice, all the usual stuff that we talk about.
But they draw a very right line, right?
So in their view, if you're going to trade tokenized US equities,
even on blockchain rails, you still have to play
by the exact same regulatory rules
that govern national security exchanges
and broker dealers today.
In other words, they don't want any shortcuts,
no exemptions and like no free passes for DeFi.
And the letter essentially asks the SEC to do three things, right?
So the first thing is they ask the SEC
to identify and classify the intermediaries
behind tokenized equity trading,
including all of the actors like inside
and involved in the DeFi protocols.
The second thing the letter does is
refuses any broad exemptions
or it asks the SEC to refuse any broad exemptions
from the definitions of exchange or broker dealer, right?
And like if you guys remember the last few years
under J.R. Gensler, this was like a huge point of contention
between the SEC and the industry.
And then the third thing that the letter asks for
is they say if the SEC does want to modernize the rules,
they have to do it through a full notice
and comment rulemaking.
So the thing that I mentioned earlier,
not a one-off exemption,
like the DeFi innovation exemption,
whatever that ends up being,
that share Atkins keeps touting, right?
So I think on its face,
some of this seems reasonable, right?
Like I think the crypto industry oftentimes
we have very knee-jerk reactions to things like this,
but I would just like encourage everyone
to kind of take a deep breath
and like take some of these things seriously, right?
Like 'cause I think there is some reasonable stuff in here.
Asking for regulatory clarity, first of all--
- That's a hot table.
That's how hot--
- I know, but it shouldn't be, right?
Like asking for regulatory clarity
through a proper rulemaking process
is literally what the crypto industry
was asking Gensler for for four years.
And there's nothing unreasonable about that, right?
So I think that's totally fair.
I want that too.
You know, wanting transparency, fair access,
market surveillance, custody standards,
all this sort of stuff.
You know, I spent almost six years at the SEC, right?
Like there are very real investor protection issues involved.
And honestly, like I think many serious crypto builders
agree that we need stronger,
just like assurances around resiliency and risk management
of tokenized assets.
I mean, this is something that like all three of us
have written about and talked about at length.
If we want to attract issuers and investors
to actually participate in these on-chain capital markets.
And by the way, there are a lot of folks in crypto
do ingest that, right?
They're engaging in good faith with the SEC
to figure out like what on-chain capital markets
would actually look like.
So I want to give a shout out to Superstate
and like Solana Policy Institute
and many others that are actually doing this.
So I think the other interesting point is like
the idea that rules should be technology neutral, right?
You hear this like all the time,
like what does it actually mean?
I think the point that Citadel makes about rules
being tech neutral is also not unreasonable, right?
'Cause it just, that could mean that like
just because a matching engine is run by code
instead of a centralized intermediary
doesn't mean that it should just like magically escape
regulation if the function is performing is the same, right?
So especially if it's something that is kind of centralized
like a lot of L2 sequencers today,
sequencers today are central, pretty central.
- Leave the L2s alone, I know, but it's true, right?
So like- - Not necessarily.
- Some of them are, right?
Like, do you wanna expand on that?
- Well, I think look like it's definitely things
get complicated when you start talking about
tokenized securities.
Like I think we all kind of laughed
when I think it was Hester Perce who felt the need
to come out and write a piece that basically said,
hey guys, remember tokenized securities are still securities.
Like there's a spectrum of crypto where it's gray,
but there's also black and white.
So tokenized security brings a lot more black and white
or a need for black and white into the conversation.
Jesse, I wanna hear your thoughts,
but really quick, I wanted to explain some context here
that I think is creating some angst over this issue.
First, for those listeners who are not as familiar
with the TRAD markets, Citadel is a leading
global massive hedge fund, an asset manager
that invests institutional money founded by Ken Griffin.
It's extraordinarily powerful.
I cannot underscore that enough on the policy, Ron.
Also, because frankly, Ken himself has donated heavily
to political candidates and super PACs.
Citadel securities, yeah, including crypto.
- Yeah, you should talk about that.
- Complication here, that's confusing.
Citadel securities, as we mentioned,
is a massive electronic market maker,
providing liquidity for investors.
They are both owned by Ken, they're distinct,
but related financial firms.
But the very confusing thing about all of this
is that Citadel securities has heavily invested in crypto,
like not through a traditional venture arm,
but a lot of strategic investments in major exchanges,
like Kraken and Emfra and all kinds of things
across the spectrum.
So a lot of people were saying,
well, why did they send this letter?
Why are they shooting themselves in the foot?
My take is that this is effectively a mechanism
to kind of, it's a long short
on where things are gonna end up.
And then there's also a theory that this is a preview
to an intent to sue the SEC on this basis.
And this is a roadmap for their lawsuit.
So that's an interesting path that we might see
and things might get really a lot
uglier than this letter.
But Jessie, go ahead, 'cause I know you have thoughts
on risk alone.
- Yeah, I think it's so interesting,
'cause this is probably the only topic so far
on the show where I'm probably in between the two of you,
because I agree that the rules
that they're emphasizing as important
are really very important.
And we all really believe in them.
What I have a problem with here
is they are the ultimate intermediary.
And of course they want to maintain a system
that's based on intermediaries.
Like it would just destroy their moat
if DeFi was able to operate without any intermediaries.
So they want tokenization to exist.
They see the benefits of it,
but only if it's done by them or in the way
that works for them.
So in many ways, this is like the least surprising filing
I've ever seen or letter to the SEC.
But the problem that I have with the letter
is not necessarily like the nuance
that V is able to read into it,
but rather that it's sort of forcing the SEC to choose
and creating like a black and white situation here.
And I think it's misclassifying what industry
is asking for because as we discussed,
and as V you mentioned, like there is this innovation
exemption idea that's out there,
but nobody knows what it's going to be.
And it's probably, I could bet on it,
is not going to be a full blanket exception
without any report that's on here.
- It's like, here's like a whole new on-chain capital markets,
like overnight.
- Yeah, I know, incentive authority works.
Like it needs to be conditional.
And narrow, we need to get a real sense
of what's required here.
So to me, like Citadel is saying,
look, SEC, you have to decide between regulation
and no regulation, no regulation's bad
for all these reasons.
And these are all intermediaries
for all the same reasons.
We're really like--
- Which is not accurate.
I think their letter definitely goes too far.
- Right.
- The letter they--
- They sweep in everything.
- Right.
- Like--
- Everything, validators, everything, yeah.
- And I think if this letter was submitted
to the SEC a year ago,
I would be more worried about its impact
because we haven't spent this entire year educating
about what all these different roles
and DeFi could be and why it's important.
Right now, I think it does speak
exactly to what you were saying, KK,
which is like, we know litigation's coming.
Rulemaking is definitely something
that probably should come about.
But like, we don't really know what's gonna happen
until we have more details on this exemption.
- Well, the other thing that I think this letter
is really important to remind everyone in crypto.
And I feel like I'm a broken record on this,
but crypto is a bubble.
We're all hanging out with each other all the time,
talking with each other all the time.
Now, it's a problem.
It's a problem from an advocacy perspective.
One of the things that I like
about my ability to advocate for crypto
is I have a crypto skeptic trad by husband,
and I use him all the time to pressure check my assumptions
to effectively bring the back
into kind of the trad perspective.
So I wanna remind everyone in crypto
that this letter is not outrageous
to a lot of traditional financial services.
So that might be troubling to crypto.
And I'm certainly not saying Citadel's right
with the concepts in these letters.
I'm saying they're wrong on a lot,
but it is a refresher and a reminder
that how we think and view these issues
is not how a lot of very powerful people
and entities think and view these issues.
So we still have work to do to educate
and to advocate, for example, on behalf of validators,
on behalf of L2s, on behalf of all
of these various market participants
that should not be regulated.
We need to explain why and we need to justify it
and we need to speak in a way
that trad markets can understand.
- And do you know what else we have to do?
Like, I know I sound like a broken record.
I feel like I've written like 50 op-eds on this.
But one thing I keep really pushing
is when the industry talks about on-chain capital markets,
we focus so much on performance, right?
Like speed, efficiency and cost.
And I think not enough on investor protection
and market integrity, right?
Like I've mentioned to you guys
the duty of best execution before.
So that's just one example, right?
It's a rule that exists in today's securities markets
to ensure that brokers feel customers' orders fairly.
That's a really important policy goal.
Like issuers and investors are not gonna participate
in capital markets where orders aren't treated fairly, right?
So how are we gonna achieve that on-chain?
What do we do about something like conflicted order routing
which basically exists everywhere in crypto trading today
in the form of MEV and like other forces?
Like there are a lot of projects taking this seriously, right?
Like flashpots has developed a lot of mechanisms
to help solve this problem on the Ethereum blockchain
and companies like Jeto and Temporal or Harmonic
have put out tools to address this.
But I really think as an industry,
we need to take those issues really seriously
because the SEC is never going to allow capital markets
to come on-chain unless we can prove
that they're fair and transparent nor should they.
And so that is, it's like something that I just,
I want the industry to start thinking
really seriously about that.
- Like V, that is 100% on point.
What I worry about here is like
Citadel securities to me is not the voice
to be saying we care about consumer protection
and give us all the best assets, everything.
And so it's very easy for DeFi
to dismiss the arguments like full stop in this letter
when what you're saying is actually really true
that they're making good points,
they're just doing it in a way that like misclassifies DeFi
and yeah, there's a lot of inaccuracies in there.
- Like Reagan leaders were the enemy for a lot of time
and now trap by, it's not just here,
it's a genius act, et cetera, like are becoming the enemy.
And so honestly, like when crypto has an enemy,
like we are bubble gets more entrenched
and it's like you're against us.
- Yeah, speaking of bubbles KK, I totally agree
that like it's actually a great reality check
to have a non-crypto like husband
because literally every other week I ask my husband
if I sound like I'm in a cult
and he's like, yeah, kind of.
- Or a friend or a mom.
- Yeah, you know, like a mom.
- Yeah.
- Or a dog, it's always good to have these people around us
that all live and breathe, like Bitcoin, come on guys.
We can't convert everyone as much as we're trying to do so.
Okay, it's a longer path.
I think that's right.
And the other thing is, look,
I think I have an immediate negative visceral reaction
when I see people trying to deal with these issues
using a sledgehammer as opposed to a scalpel
in the words of commissioner purse in her privacy piece.
And we have spent so many years
with the sledgehammer regulatory approach
and what is likely the best route forward for crypto
is a scalpel.
Now, it's a lot harder to do that
as we've seen with legislation,
but Citadel's sledgehammer letter was absurd.
Again, not absurd to the trademarks,
but absurd in how they were sweeping everyone
into something that didn't make sense from a very technical
perspective.
- Yeah, yeah, I agree with that.
- Okay, so we have another meaty topic
that we're going to move to in a minute,
but before we do so, another word from our sponsors.
- Hey, founders and developers,
if you're looking to bring on-chain trading
to your product, wallet or platform,
check out the new Uniswap Trading API from Uniswap Labs.
It's your plug and play gateway to global on-chain liquidity.
No deep crypto experience required
and no need to manage complex integrations
or ongoing maintenance.
With the Uniswap Trading API,
you'll get enterprise grade on-chain execution,
combining both on-chain and off-chain sources
for the most competitive prices.
Simply put, more liquidity, less complexity.
And this isn't just any API.
It connects directly to the Uniswap protocol,
which has securely processed over $3.3 trillion
in total volume with zero hacks.
So stop worrying about liquidity infrastructure
and focus on building your product.
Get access to the same liquidity
that powers billions in swaps through one powerful API.
Visit hub.uniswap.org to learn more.
- So two absolutely massive news items
from the CFTC this week,
speaking of good news, positive news,
after talking about Citadel.
The first was the acting chair, Caroline Pham,
who has just been on a terror of progress,
announced that listed spot crypto products
can change on CFTC registered futures exchanges.
So as a refresher, those are called
designated contract markets or DCM.
I wanna provide a little bit more background there
'cause I am formerly the chief legal officer
of a DCM and a crypto spot market.
So derivatives or futures are traded on DCMs.
So meaning that up until now,
spot crypto trading in the US has not happened on DCMs.
It's mainly happened on kind of crypto native platforms
that aren't regulated by the CFTC or SEC.
They're subject to this horrible patchwork
of state licensing, like state money transmitter licenses,
New York bit licenses, et cetera.
Some of the spot trading also happens on kind of tread
by platforms like Robinhood
and there's other licenses that can be involved.
But the CFTC's primary authority
is over the derivatives markets.
It's not over spot crypto markets, but the big change.
So, and this is huge, is that chair Pham came forward
and was basically like DCMs can list spot crypto for trading.
This was previewed months ago
so the industry actually had chance to comment,
but now it's official, official.
And we have already seen the nominal launching
the first ever leverage spot crypto exchange.
So I want to get thoughts from my other hosts,
but a very nerdy point here.
Margin trades in spot crypto are actually already considered
by the CFTC to be retail leveraged commodity transactions,
which means that under like those specific transactions
under the Commodity Exchange Act are a carve out.
Like there's a carve out in the Commodities Exchange Act
that designates what the CFTC has jurisdiction over.
That says that certain retail commodity transactions
can be treated by the law as if they were futures contracts.
So these transactions were already kind of like a secret
exception to the whole no spot trading on DCMs,
but no one was really using this.
Now it's a question mark as to where that like,
is that where the jurisdiction comes from?
So I'll stop talking, but the TLDR of all of this,
like from an educational perspective,
is there has never been like clear guidance from the CFTC
that futures exchanges can list spot crypto
as leveraged retail commodity transactions until now.
And the real utility is that all of these DCMs
can now offer retail access to long and short crypto
like with leverage.
And it could also hopefully for centralized exchanges
or for DCMs make it a lot easier for those exchanges
to offer these products and to navigate all of this
without dealing with the state by state patchwork
if they rely on federal preemption.
So huge advantage there, everybody's going to want a DCM.
So I know that V had some questions.
I'll turn it.
- I did, I love asking you all how many CFTC questions.
So my question was like, like a competition one,
almost like all of that is super interesting.
But like when I saw this, my first thought was,
oh, like was just one company like granted,
like permission to do this.
And it seemed to come out of nowhere.
And so like that made me think about,
like I don't know if you guys remember,
but when like the SEC was basically forced
by the DC Circuit Court to approve spot Bitcoin ETFs,
like they did it in a very particular way,
which is they approved all 11 applications at the same time.
So like the first 11 applications,
they approved them as a group.
And I think they did that because they didn't want to give
like any one market participant a leg up or an unfair like
advantage or a head start.
So like that was kind of my first thought
when I saw the Bitnomial news.
So like do you, can you shed any light on that?
- It's a great question.
So Bitnomials actually unique.
I'm a fan of Bitnomial.
They hold a DCM license.
They also hold a derivatives clearing organization,
a DCO license, which is for clearing.
And they are also a futures commission merchant and FCM.
So that is nearly a full suite of CFTC licenses.
And it's what's called a vertically integrated structure.
So there's actually four pieces of a derivative market,
the exchange, the DCM, the clearing house,
the DCO, the broker or the futures commission merchant,
the FCM and then the matching engine, like the technology.
So Bitnomial structure is a one stop shop.
So traders don't have to involve traditional brokers
and Bitnomial kind of controls with different multiple layers
as opposed to relying on a bunch of different third parties.
That explains in my mind why they were kind of first to--
- 'Cause they already had all of the license,
like the registrations they needed.
- Exactly.
And look, you don't need all those licenses
to be a DCM and to list spot crypto.
You don't.
But what it does is Bitnomial structure,
it decreases dependencies.
And they already offered futures perps.
They're actually the one DCM in America
to call their perpetual like product a perp
and they were the first to list perps.
A lot of people forget about that and options.
And now this week, they launched the first ever
leveraged retail spot, crypto exchange.
So again, my take is that they had this
good like ready to go with this guidance,
like with what, you know, fans' guidance.
There's nothing preventing other DCMs
from moving forward and doing what Bitnomial is doing.
The other interesting point I'll make
is there aren't that many DCMs.
Like there really are not.
It's a very small group of crypto DCMs.
There's a lot of companies looking into getting a DCM.
It's quite a process.
It's quite an undertaking.
But I would not compare it to registering with the SEC
because, you know, it has historically been more realistic
to get a DCM than to register as a securities exchange.
And there are crypto DCMs.
Whereas as we have heard, there's like,
there's also only like five like registered securities
exchanges.
Yeah, exactly.
Like there aren't that many of them.
Yeah, well, there's, I think there's more than that.
Maybe you tell them. But yeah.
Yeah, it's a small number.
It's hard to get these licenses.
So I'm the other, it's a notable macro point.
Like we're not tomorrow going to see like a huge flood of DCMs.
It's a process.
And the entities that are already well-positioned
with crypto futures, if I were them,
I would obviously be thinking really strategically
about how like what direction do we want to take this guidance?
On a regulator strategy point, I also
think it's sort of interesting because the CFTC SEC,
like whether it's totally true or not,
like the crypto industry has always been like,
which one do we want?
We should be pit one against the other.
Which one's better?
Which one has more power, which was going to enforce less?
And recently there's been all this news and evidence as well
of them working together to try and push the industry forward
as well as some other initiatives.
But once we're going on lately at the CFTC,
it really is sort of showing me that they're
trying to push forward and show themselves capable
of regulating this space.
And I feel like it's sort of a race
to regulate a little bit in interesting innovative ways
between the CFTC and SEC.
And like if you layer that competitive aspect of it
over the market structure bill and the drafting of it,
it's sort of to me seems like they're all sort of trying
to show legislators like this is how this agency can do it.
And the CFTC is taking a strong position here of like,
look, we as regulators are doing something really special.
We're allowing new things that are going to work
and be safe while we keep close tabs on it.
Yeah, it's kind of like the CFTC is Project Crypto.
And it's like, I think I said this on a prior episode.
Like, if you don't show that you can do a good job,
you're going to get fired.
And so like, that's what they're trying to avoid, right?
But it's good.
I think it's like a race to the top in a lot of ways to show.
I love the endpoint on the prior episode
and be hitting the gate where if this SEC hadn't like fumbled
the ball during the Gensler administration,
the SEC might have just effectively moved
into the Pat of Raleigh.
Yeah, the primary regulator.
So like that's a sad missed opportunity.
But yeah, look, like chair fam is making a lot of progress,
a lot of like very quickly.
And the sense is that she really wants to get a lot of,
a lot done before she moves forward.
Now we finally very realistically have the prospect
of a CFTC chair.
You know, Mike Selig, like it looks like smooth sailing,
sailing Fortnim.
I am a big fan of future chair, Selig.
He's whip smart.
You know, he actually really knows and understands crypto.
I was very disappointed when there
was that kerfuffle over the Brian Quinten's nomination.
That was ugly.
We don't need to get into that on the pod.
But I think chair Selig will be great.
And you know, it's good that chair fam or acting chair fam
is really getting shit done before she's heading out the door.
I'm feeling very hopeful today.
But I also think like the work that's being done,
I don't want to say it's just the CFTC.
But since that's what we're talking about right now,
buy regulators to show like this can work in a regulated
space is actually great for the industry
because this is a narrative of cryptos unregulated.
It's full of criminals and that narrative
can fall apart when you see like actively regulated
institutions doing this in a way that makes finance better.
Yeah.
And we know that I want to be clear.
Like none of us necessarily think regulation good,
like no regulation bad.
But what we're talking about here is crypto finance,
like crypto trading, if it's not decentralized, hey, guys,
like if it's a centralized entity facilitating crypto spot
trading, guys, it should be regulated.
I actually don't think that's a hot take.
And one of the things that I still have PTSD over is 2022,
where a major contributing factor, you know,
I was at a DeFi protocol at that time.
And I was so furious because there was so much
demonization of DeFi in the press narrative
during the crypto crash.
And we were all like, it's not DeFi that screwed this up, guys.
It's actually CFI masquerading as DeFi.
And yes, Celsius probably should have been regulated.
Like, clearly.
So OK, rant over, but that I'm still
going to continue that for many of us.
I was wondering if you were going to name the--
I think all there to that pain and different overlapping ways.
I got like a lot of gray hair over that time period,
as did everyone who was looking for you at this time.
And occasionally I am like, have we learned nothing from 2022?
I actually think this episode is more positive.
And maybe it's because like, we have a common animation.
We're just rad by.
But I do think that like, over the past week,
if we judge how crypto is doing and the tenor based
on crypto Twitter, it seems like we're all sort of unified again.
So that's good.
Look at that.
I'm sure that will last, you know, a few months.
A few months.
Like, OK, Jessie.
And you know, one of the other things I have to add,
on another positive note, another huge news
broke from the CFTC, from acting chair fam.
She also announced a pilot program
for tokenized collateral in the derivatives market.
So we just talked about derivatives.
We just talked about DCMs.
I love this.
Like, this was inevitable.
This was a long time coming.
I remember during the very, very dark days
before the sun came out in the crypto regulatory environment,
there was this massive tokenization summit in February of 2024,
where it was basically all of the US regulators, global regulators,
talking about tokenization.
And they talked a lot about tokenized collateral
in the derivatives market.
And to be specific, this covers ETH, Bitcoin, and USCC.
And the reason they talked about it
is because I've always thought this is just a fantastic use case
for crypto because it's very easily understandable.
It's very easy to see the utility.
And I'm talking atomic settlement, more transparency,
automation, increased capital efficiency, cost savings,
several other big moves forward.
It's innovation in the derivatives market.
I remember-- I'm old enough to remember
when moving to T plus one settlement,
faster settlement than before was huge.
Now we're shrinking that gap more.
So in some ways, this feels abrupt to certain people.
But I think if you were really focused,
or if you were kind of plugged into the trade markets,
as I was before I joined crypto, I
was with the SIBO, SIBO Digital, the DCM.
And you could understand why people were excited about that,
or more conceptually open to this than a lot of other facets
of crypto.
So that's another huge piece of positive news from the CFTC.
I love it.
Nice.
Thanks for the roundup.
Yeah, OK.
So everybody's probably sick of hearing me talk.
And we've spent way too much time talking
about TradFi on this podcast.
So we're going to wrap up with our third topic.
It's actually super cool.
And I'm going to hand it over to our AI ZAR Jesse,
take it as a review.
I love it's cool.
It's actually like a little scary.
But essentially what came out last week
is that anthropic did a study showing
that AI's changing how we should think about security
on chain, which is a topic that we've covered before.
But I think it's a topic that we need to continue to cover,
because it's only getting harder.
Essentially, the security paradigm
has changed because agents aren't just assisting hackers
anymore, but rather they can be the hacker.
They're creating and running an entire exploit from end
to end the same way that a sophisticated human actor would.
But they're doing it faster, cheaper, and with endless stamina,
because they don't have to sleep.
They can work all the time.
And so I think we need to be a little bit concerned
and really understand what happened here
and what this study says.
So I'm going to break it down a little bit.
So essentially, anthropic created a blockchain simulator,
and they put AI agents into it, asking them
to do something really simple, which
is just look at the real smart contracts that
have already been exploited in the wild
and see if they can independently do it again.
So essentially, look at all these smart contracts,
find the hacks, and see if you can recreate them.
Wait, and Smece, for listeners who aren't familiar
with anthropic, tell us a little bit about what it is.
Because candidly, I didn't know anthropic
until I dug into this.
Got it.
If you've ever used Claude, that is from anthropic.
So it's essentially-- it's way more complicated than this,
but essentially, it's a competitor to open AI.
So some people use chat2VD.
Some people use Claude.
I use both.
So I'm not here to say one or the other,
but it's one that's very focused on security and safety,
and it frequently takes the opposite position
of other large AI shops about the dangers associated with AI.
And if you really want to understand security and AI,
just go to anthropic's website, and they
have amazing primers to help you understand
how you should be worried about it.
So they're really testing the products
that they're putting out there into the world.
And that includes testing how it could
hack different scenarios.
They actually chose smart contracts
because they could then quantify how much money could
be stolen by how much effort they put it
and how much money goes in.
And that's why smart contracts were targeted here.
Was it like anti-crypto or anything like that?
Like it was a test that they did.
And I think it was a test that actually can really help
the crypto industry understand the problem here.
So essentially, just to get back to exactly what they found
was the AI agents acting autonomously
were able to recreate exploits that already happened.
So that's number one.
And they were able to do it over and over again,
creating hundreds of millions of dollars of losses.
Obviously, this was an assimilator.
And OK, so we've seen these hacks before.
Is it really that big of a deal?
But then they made them test this on smart contracts
that they weren't trained on.
So how training works for LLMs is essentially
to build an LLM, you put all this information
in there to make it a foundational set of learnings.
And that's called pre-training.
And then you release it, essentially.
So remember when you used to use chat GPT,
and sometimes it would say like, this does not--
this is not included in our pre-training.
Information are our knowledge stops here.
So if you pre-trained until January 1,
and then you release it, if you ask about something six months
later, they might not know about it.
Now that's gotten better with something
called reinforcement learning and post-training and web search.
But essentially, it's very important to know
what an LLM has been pre-trained on.
But they were able to hack smart contracts
that they knew nothing about beforehand.
So essentially, they're not hacking from memory.
They're hacking from learning.
So they're learning based on prior exploits
and figuring out how to do new, different exploits, OK?
That's so creepy, Jessie.
I just have to stop.
Wait, wait, wait, there's an X creepy part.
Because it got worse.
So then they were like, OK, let's point the agents
at brand new contracts that were just put out
into the ecosystem with no known issues.
Like, they weren't any issues spotted.
And within a short period of time,
the agents found two zero-day exploits.
Zero days, essentially, just like the builders have had zero days
to fix any vulnerabilities following release.
And they executed exploits.
And they made money that costs more than what the agents cost.
And why that's important is that the agents are sort of programmed
to make money, right?
So they know how to make enough money to offset any costs.
And as you watch them learning and getting better,
it was getting cheaper to do this for the agents.
So each contract that they tested, smart contracts
for different vulnerabilities cost about $1, OK?
So they could do 1,000 smart contracts for $1,000 like this.
That's insane.
So the big story to me is not like AI can hack smart contracts.
Like, OK, we sort of knew that.
What does that mean?
There's hack all the time.
It's probably happening already.
I think it's more that these agents can reason, iterate,
use dev tooling, and autonomously execute a full chain attack
from start to finish in a faster and cheaper way than humans.
So the security vector has struck.
Like, if you put a smart contract up there that controls funds,
you have to know it's perfect because an attacker can now
spend $1 to surface every latent issue and continuously
harvest and automate a hacking machine.
And I think this is so important because, one,
it's really something that we need to think about
and why we need to focus more on cyber security more than ever.
But two, I am so excited about this idea of AI and crypto.
The number of podcasts about AI crypto intersection
or blogs or whatever, it's just endless, right?
And we're still trying to figure out,
like, how does this all work together?
But my question is like, and I'm excited about it, too.
Don't get me wrong, as you can probably tell.
But I'm just--
I love the passion.
I'm just not sure we're ready because what
happens when agents are on chain day to day, like with 402
or with any other sort of trading mechanism?
How do we deal with prompt injection?
How do we deal with loss of control scenarios?
Like, we're still trying to figure out
how to deal with the vulnerabilities and smart contracts
that, like, DPRK can get at or humans can get at.
And so the question now is like, how do we really respond?
And it's the end, in my mind, of passive security.
We mean more active security measures.
I love this because I don't know if you guys know this
about me, but I love post-apocalyptic movies.
It's like my thing.
Like, my husband will be like, there's
a new show where everyone has died and gone underground.
I think he would love it.
And like, this is very aligned with that.
Like, first they come for our smart contracts,
then they come to take over our homes.
OK, anyway, but look, I think these issues are huge.
We talk a lot about regulation conceptually.
But I always think of, in crypto, there's
three big buckets of risk.
One is like AML, KYC, criminal risk.
One is regulatory, SEC, CFTC.
The third is just security.
And a good company has a strategy
to deal with all three of those risks that
is both proactive and reactive.
And the security prong is often less legal and more--
the builders, the technical people, the CTO, that had a security.
And I think your point is spot on,
is we need to start looking down the pipeline
and see what's coming for us on the security sphere
to make sure we're prepared.
That was a pretty good way to end it.
Much more positive than mine.
We'll get there.
We are strong.
OK, so we have two more super quick things
before we wrap up for this week.
One, V has a really important shout out.
So I'm going to toss it to V.
Yeah, so just really quickly, I wanted
to draw attention to the samurai wallet case.
So this is a case that's almost identical to the tornado cash
case.
And what happened here was the prosecutors
agreed to allow the two co-founders to plead guilty
to the least serious charge of operating an unlicensed money
transmitter business, which carries a maximum of five years
as opposed to taking the case to trial
and taking their chances at trial on all three charges, which
also involved money laundering, and likely, to be honest,
getting the max sentence of 25 years,
because the case had been reassigned
to Judge Denise Cote of the SCNY, who people don't know.
She's one of the harshest sentences on the court.
So Keoni Rodriguez, one of the co-founders,
ended up getting the max five years for the one charge
that he pled to.
And he's set to report to prison on December 19.
He has started a petition for a pardon.
So I urge all of you who care about developer rights
and just the human impact of this case to sign it.
We'll link it in the show notes.
And I've also posted it on my ex-account.
Seriously, important, shout out.
And we should talk more about this on a different episode,
because the three of us are very familiar with the process
of plea deals.
And a lot of people don't really understand the pressure
and the calculus that goes into pleading out.
And unfortunately, to some degree,
these individuals were in the wrong time at the wrong place.
Or just--
I don't want to call them--
Judge matters.
How much your joint matters, how you negotiate and things
like that, it just makes such a difference,
and it can impact your life forever.
Yeah, what you're going to sign too.
Yeah, yeah, which is frustrating to say the least.
So thank you for that, the important shout out.
And of course, this is the second week of our weekly shout out
of Crypto Good News.
So please send us your nomination, send us your ideas,
valuable organizations, fun stories, interesting use cases.
We have a great one that Jesse's going to touch on today.
Yeah, thanks, everyone, for sending ideas in.
And what we was just talking about is so important,
so it's hard to follow it.
But here's something else that just gives you
a little bit more hope about crypto.
So essentially, there was a huge fire in Hong Kong.
Probably many of y'all heard of it.
Over 150 people have died so far.
And it's like the biggest fire since post-1940s.
And essentially, it was burning for days
in a certain apartment complex.
And lots of stuff happens all over the world.
It's easy to ignore it.
News is so crazy right now.
But a lot of crypto companies did not ignore this one.
And they donated millions of dollars
to help repair and help some of the victims
or families of decedents.
And it just sort of shows that in all the crap
and in all the news, there's a lot of good things
and good people happening.
And especially in this time in the world,
I think it's really important for us
to continue to highlight them.
16 million, absolutely.
We are global citizens because we are crypto companies.
We are borderless.
But it still means we take care of humans on this Earth.
So that's a beautiful moment and a reflection.
Good for those companies.
Shout out to those companies for being good citizens.
So next week, we're gonna have a special privacy episode
that immediately follows my participation
on the SEC's financial surveillance and privacy round table.
Don't know how I finagled and invite to that, guys.
But excited to talk all about, it'll be great.
Stark where the OGs of ZK, TAC, and all that fun stuff.
And we are going to have our first ever guess
on Decks in the City.
So prize test.
Surprise test, good luck.
So we will see you next week.
That is it for this week's episode of Deck from the City.